<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ganesh Kadam&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ganesh Kadam&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 11:00:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meganeshkadam.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Pune June 2016 meetup</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 11:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;python-pune-meetup-june-2016-data-dojo&#34;&gt;Python Pune Meetup June 2016 : Data Dojo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python Pune Meetup organized the Data Dojo on 25th June 2016 at Red Hat, Pune. This time its was a kind of hackathon for exploring the Python Pandas,NumPy and Matplotlib that we learned in the last seroes of Data Science meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the data sets that were used for Data Dojo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/adult/adult.data&#34;&gt;Adult Data: Male/Female names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.in/resources/indian-railways-time-table-trains-available-reservation-03082015/download&#34;&gt;Train Time Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; explained what are the pre-requisites for Data Dojo, and what actually it means. Later &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; gave us two data sets to explore. Attendees have to create a group of 3 each and choose any one of them or the one of their own choice and upload it to their repo on Git Hub and share it on meetup page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 25 Pythonistas turned up for this hackathon as expected, but the one&amp;rsquo;s who came tried their hands on with Python Pandas. Most of them were intermediates in Python, though every one in this meetup did explored the data sets. Good thing about this meetup was that, most of the attendees knew Pyhton, and just had never heard about Pandas,Numpy and matplotlib. Data Dojo gave them an opportunity to learn these libraries in Python, and take away for them was, Pandas and introductory Data Science skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally asked every one to present their work to all, and the ones who did got some goodies as well!
Here are links to the work done by some attendees :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanayseven/python_data_dojo&#34;&gt;Tanay Prabhudesai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ketulgupta1995/Python-Data-Dojo&#34;&gt;Ketul Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vksgaikwad3/pypunedojo&#34;&gt;Vikas Gaikwad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chaiku/PyPuneDataDojo2016&#34;&gt;Chaitanya Kukde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our upcoming Python Pune meetup, we will be learning about the scikit-learn basics.Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; for giving us this opportunity to volunteer for awesome meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: i want 2 do project. tell me wat 2 do.</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 07:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since my college days, I have been trying to focus on my interests,
and the domain that I always wanted to work on. I started attending
various meetups to keep myself updated with upcoming and new
technologies used in organizations. This helped me learn or at least
get to know about the new emerging technologies such as Docker,
OpenStack, OpenShift etc. I have met many people who are so eager to
share their knowledge and want newbies to start with Open Source
contributions. One such amazing experience I had, was at May Fedora
Pune Meetup held on 14th May 2016 at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No other experience in this world can be so awesome than to get my copy
of book signed by the author himself. Apart from discussing the pain
points for newbies, those who are finding it difficult to start with
their Open Source contributions, we got an opportunity to ask so many
questions to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shakthimaan&#34;&gt;@mbuf&lt;/a&gt;. He had come to
Pune for an Emacs meetup that was held the previous day, and showed up
the following day for the Fedora meetup. Most of the attendees met him
for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting back to the review of his book, I would say it is one of the
must-read books for all those who want to get started contributing to
Open Source software. This book really covers everything pretty well
that anyone with no or some experience in F/OSS would need to
know. This book clears all the essential checkpoints that one should
know, like how to communicate in the Open Source community, how to
program, how to start on the project you want to work, how to present
yourself etc. to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book has answers to all the questions that a newbie would face
while working on Open Source projects and is good to keep it handy for
your reference, wherever you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ten chapters in this book. Starting from &amp;ldquo;Chapter 1. Mailing
Guidelines&amp;rdquo; up to the last &amp;ldquo;Chapter 10. Sustenance&amp;rdquo;, I have never felt
bored while reading it. As soon as I proceeded chapter by chapter I
realized that the book is really well written and the content written
in each chapter is very important for one and all. Though some of them
might be very basic for others, but they are really essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becoming the kind of person who believes that these things are
important for you — for helping you to learn and to keep you
motivated. As with all creative arts, the most effective way to become
a master is to imitate the mind-set of masters — not just
intellectually but emotionally as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, as the following modern Zen poem has it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;To follow the path,

look to the master,

follow the master,

walk with the master,

see through the master,

become the master.

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above lines are from one of the reference links
&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shakthimaan&#34;&gt;@mbuf&lt;/a&gt; gave in the meetup :
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.catb.org/~esr/faqs/hacker-howto.html&#34;&gt;The Cathedral and the Bazaar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are more amazing quotes in each chapter in this book and are
motivational. So what are you waiting for? Do order this from :
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.in/want-project-tell-wat-do/dp/9351741877&#34;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;
really worth every penny!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more about &amp;ldquo;mbuf&amp;rdquo; on his website :
&lt;a href=&#34;http://shakthimaan.com/&#34;&gt;Shakthi Kannan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His IRC nick is mbuf on Freenode #dgplug channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy Hacking!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis using Python Pandas</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 04:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Python Pune meetup was held at Amazatic solutions, on 28th May 2016. This meetup was focused on Data Analysis using Python Pandas for Data Science Series.Below are some of the highlights of this workshop which were covered using Case Study :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Numpy basics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Pandas Data Structures and basics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Loading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Wrangling (Clean, Transform, Merge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Aggregation and grouping operations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Exploratory Data Analysis and Descriptive Statistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Plotting and Visualization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; was the speaker for this workshop. He is a Data Engineer at NEC Corporation of America and also a regular member of Python Pune Meetup and Data Scientist Meetup of Pune. I missed the first session on Data Science in last month which mainly focused on the basics of Data Science, Machine Learing and Algorithms and related concepts. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; he covered few of the basic concepts in this meetup again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datascience is full framework.Machine learning deals with building models.Two major languages used in Datascience are : # R and Python
Apart from some syntactical differences in R and Python, both the languages offer the datastructure most oftenly used in Datacience i.e
Dataframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a typical Datascience workflow, most of the time of Data Scientists is consumed to get the data,analyze the data,sepeartion of data,and cleaning of data, that means almost 70% of the total work in intial phase. Later comes the actual business logic and model building.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; cleared this understanding about the Data Science.Most of the people wind up enrolling in to some classes and generally don&amp;rsquo;t understand the actual concepts, there is really a need of efforts if you want to be a Data Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We faced few technical issues during the meetup, in the mean time &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan/1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; started with the basics of numpy. The learning curve to be a good Data Scientist, includes the understanding of python libraries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python-pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scikitlearn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following are few comparisions between numpy and python pandas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;numpy&#34;&gt;numpy:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built for fast array processing, vector operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 times faster then list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made for scientific calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eg :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import numpy as np
imprt pandas as pd

ni = np.array(list)
 type (n1) gives o/p :numpy.ndarray

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;numpy function arrange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;7np.arrange(10)  # bydefault int
for float use : np.arrange(10, dtype=np.64)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;python-pandas&#34;&gt;python pandas :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datastructure series - 1d numpy array stores data. its like column in dataframe context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;series also has the index and the value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To access values in series :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser1.values

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To acess the value in index :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser1.index

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can customize the indexes, and can also have duplicates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser2=[1,211,2,1,2,1,2], index=[a,d,d,s,a,s]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can change the values in series using index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dataframe is collection of series like excel sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More the memory More data can be analysed in python pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about python pandas, here is the beautiful website for beginners which has the cook book by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/b0rk&#34;&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt; and lots of tutorials as well: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/version/0.15.2/tutorials.html&#34;&gt;Python Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed about the Matplotlib, in one of the case studies.This case study was taken from the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;,a website focused on learning Data Science and also has hackathons for the same.Case Study was about the Titanic-Machine Learning from Disaster.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; explained python pandas can be used effectively to extract the data from the available resources, and build the usefull models.Matplotlib is the library used to mainly produce the charts related to the data. You can generate plots, histograms, power spectra, bar charts, errorcharts, scatterplots, etc, with just a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we disscusssed about the next meetup in which we will be conducting a Hackathon,in continuation with this meetup and try to do some hands on wiht Python Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; for giving us the opportunity to learn and volunteer for this meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are few resources from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; that we used for this meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sudarshan1413/python_pandas_meetup_2016&#34;&gt;Python Pune Data Analysis with Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cin.ufpe.br/~embat/Python%20for%20Data%20Analysis.pdf&#34;&gt;Python for Data Analysis Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gerrit Isue</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/gerrit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 01:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/gerrit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was working on shell a script. Now that it was complete I need to send that script for review.So I started to work on this. Unfortunately I got the following error which took me almost took a day to resolve on my side. I decided not to ask my mentors until and unless I am not able to rsolve this issue. This has been common issue amongst all of us interns!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[gkadam@dhcp201-114 cert-openstack-scripts]$ git review -R
Could not connect to gerrit.
Enter your gerrit username: gkadam@redhat.com
Trying again with ssh://gkadam@redhat.com@code.engineering.redhat.com:22/cert-openstack-scripts
&amp;lt;traceback object at 0x7fa7a448cb00&amp;gt;
We don&#39;t know where your gerrit is. Please manually create a remote
named &amp;quot;gerrit&amp;quot; and try again.
Could not connect to gerrit at ssh://gkadam@redhat.com@code.engineering.redhat.com:22/cert-openstack-acripts
Traceback (most recent call last):
File &amp;quot;/usr/bin/git-review&amp;quot;, line 11, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt;
sys.exit(main())
File &amp;quot;/usr/lib/python2.7/site-packages/git_review/cmd.py&amp;quot;, line 1534, in main
sys.exit(e.EXIT_CODE)
AttributeError: &#39;GitReviewException&#39; object has no attribute &#39;EXIT_CODE&#39;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After going through lots of google serarches I realized that, the things that were going wrong are already mentioned in the error code that I was getting. Before this I made a very silly mistake of deleting the existing file in that directory from which I have to send the file for review. So just after knowing this issue, I copied the new script in to the same directory again. Then I renamed to it&amp;rsquo;s earlier name and performed following steps :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloned the repository to new location :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- --&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[gkadam@dhcp201-114 ~]$ git clone ssh://gkadam@code.engineering.redhat.com:22/cert-openstack-scripts
Cloning into &#39;cert-openstack-scripts&#39;...
Checking connectivity... done.
warning: remote HEAD refers to nonexistent ref, unable to checkout.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added the remote repository as we can see in the above error!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- --&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[gkadam@dhcp201-114 cert-openstack-scripts]$ git remote add gerrit ssh://gkadam@code.engineering.redhat.com:22/cert-openstack-scripts
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then did a git review after adding the script and commiting it in that dierctory :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- --&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[gkadam@dhcp201-114 cert-openstack-scripts]$ git review -R
Your change was committed before the commit hook was installed.
Amending the commit to add a gerrit change id.
remote: Processing changes: new: 1, refs: 1, done.
remote: (W) 9dedc09: commit subject &amp;gt;65 characters; use shorter first paragraph
remote: (W) 9dedc09: too many commit message lines longer than 70 characters; manually wrap lines
remote:
remote: New Changes:
remote:https://code.engineering.redhat.com/gerrit/73014 Add user validation, and create functions : create_member,create_network and remote:
To ssh://gkadam@code.engineering.redhat.com:22/cert-openstack-scripts
* [new branch]      HEAD -&amp;gt; refs/publish/master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the workaround for my problem that I was facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the link to the similar issue on git : &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.github.com/articles/error-remote-head-refers-to-nonexistent-ref-unable-to-checkout/&#34;&gt;Git remote HEAD Issue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Pune March 2016 meetup</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 12:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python Pune Meetup March 2016 was organized at Amazatic Solutions on 26th March 2016. Following was the agenda for this meetup :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshop : Vim &amp;amp; frameworks by Devchandra L&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk1 : Libvert Programming API by Amol Kahat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk2 : Fedora Hubs by Dhriti Shikhar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@cyipro started the meetup initially with an introduction to Python and OpenSource. The majority of attendees were students so it was very helpful for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amol Kahat started with the first talk of this meet up on libvirt-api he is a Red Hat intern. libvert is a toolkit to interact with the virtualization capabilities of recent versions of Linux. It is a free and opensource software available under GPL license. Amol explained about the virtualization technology, hypervisors and how the libvert-api is different from the other available options. To know more information on libvirt-apis, here is the link :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;Libvert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@vega_yaa is the organizer of Pune Vim Users Group. The main motto of this group is to help people start using vim and to share knowledge about the same. @vega_yaa started with vim workshop after Amol&amp;rsquo;s talk by explaining a little history of vi and vim, later on also explained few differences in bertween them.It was for all the novices as well as for the people who already use vim for their daily use but are unaware of the vim&amp;rsquo;s power. Starting with very basics, he explained why we should use vim, and its magic once you get used to it. Attendees got a hands-on session on vim, for example starting with how you should open multiple files using vim, how to use alias, Buffermode in vim, various options like split, vsplit, tabnewfile, code folding in vim etc.Though it sounds very simple, knowing essentials of vim will definitely boost the productivity. Here are the slides for this workshop :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PuneVimUser/magical-vim&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@DhritiShikhar gave a talk on Fedora Hubs post vim workshop. She is a final year Engineering student from a Sinhagad college of Engineering, Pune and very active in OpenSource contributions. She is one of the owners of Fedora Hubs project as well. She explained why this project was started and also showed how one should start with the contribution to any open source project. Fedora Hubs is still in active development stage and due for release in next 3 months. Here is the link for the Fedora Hubs project on Pagure :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs&#34;&gt;Fedora Hubs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the meetup ended with a good response and feedbacks from attendees. We had some discussion for next meetup. It was as a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March 2016</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 11:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog3/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-9&#34;&gt;Week # 9&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, few issues in my bash script are resolved. Now I need to test it on the other environments and work further on the validation part, and optimization.The script has helped me a lot in understanding OpenStack-APIs, CURL concepts, and other bash scripting skills. Also, I am attending the weekly #rdo meetings on IRC giving me a good insight of what all things are coming up in the next release of RDO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the links I used while writing bash script:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.openstack.org/api-ref-networking-v2-ext.html#addRouterInterface&#34;&gt;OpenStack netwowking API Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.openstack.org/wiki/Neutron/APIv2-specification&#34;&gt;Neutron API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ask.openstack.org/&#34;&gt;Ask OpenStack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://curl.haxx.se/docs/httpscripting.html&#34;&gt;CURL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tldp.org/LDP/abs/html/&#34;&gt;Bash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given an opportunity to volunteer the Python Pune meetup. It was a nice experience in February devsprint2016 #1, and a great Learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also volunteered for the gnuNIFY 2016 last month. Attended few workshops as well. @ramky took an awsome Python workshop, he started with absolute basics, and at the end, he also discussed on Big Data, Machine Learning and few advanced topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have started to prepare for the Red Hat certifications as well.Initially, we have started with RHCSA, then we will focus on RHCE and then on Red Hat OpenStack Certification track.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python3 devsprint2016#1</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/devsprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 01:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/devsprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge is Power.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#python-pune&lt;/strong&gt; meetup organized &lt;em&gt;devsprint#1&lt;/em&gt; this Saturday i.e on 20-02-2016. It was the first dev sprint for me as well and my first meet up as a host for the day, thanks to @cyipro and @yudocca for giving me this opportunity. This dev sprint was quite different than the previous ones. We have asked attendees to select the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; projects of their own choice to work on during the dev sprint. There were many of them who could find themselves suitable projects and started working on, but few were completely new to &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contribution and so it took some time for them to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very beginning of this dev sprint, @ciypro explained about getting started with the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contributions and how one should find the projects of his/her own choice. We found most of them had the same problem in getting the projects of their interests as there are a number of projects available and for newbies, it is really very difficult to get the starting point for the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contribution. Here are few links where I searched for the projects and helped few attendees to start with: - &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatcanidoforfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/openstack/+bugs&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatcanidoformozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have selected the bug from link &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/congress/+bug/1415199&#34;&gt;Congress&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;OpenStack low hanging fruits&lt;/em&gt; . Here is the link for the link &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstack/congress&#34;&gt;Congress&lt;/a&gt; on git. Currently, the installation is available only for Debian. @cyipro have suggested me to update the process for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CentOS&lt;/em&gt; and send a patch for the same. Quite easier for me to get started! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this dev sprint, I got to know how you should get help for the projects you are working on and also the end result of working collaboratively on a single project. One of the attendees was not able to find the project, but he started working on one of the projects with few others at dev sprint and at the end of the dev sprint this group was actually able to send a small patch for that project. They all were first timers and were happy to work collaboratively for that bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this was experimental dev sprint, not all of the attendees could find the projects and send the patches, but everyone was satisfied at the end of the day, because for many this meet up formed as a platform to learn and start with #OpenSource contributions. We had a feedback session at the end from each of the attendees and we got many positive feedbacks for this dev sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nice experience for me and got many new things added to my knowledge base. I have started preparing for more such dev sprints to happen in coming days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning is the eye of the mind. Keep Learning&lt;/em&gt; -French Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February 2016</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 10:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-5-jashn&#34;&gt;Week # 5 : [Jashn]&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working on a script to automate few tasks related to my work and was facing some issues. I discussed my issues with @rshbhdas initially.@rshbhdas helped me to understand how the script should work. Later I also discussed few thing about sed and awk with @savitojs for my shell script. He is a System Admin for our project. We also had a bit of discussion about a Chef, Puppet, and Ansible. I got to know how he handles all the machines with just the scripts written in shell and python. @ramkrsna is one of a senior member of our team. He is Principal Software Engineer at Red Hat and looks after crucial part of our project. I had a short discussion with him on my script. He was quitebusy but still, later on, he had a look at my script and asked me to write the script in a different way. @ramkrsna suggested me to use Curl with Bash and API&amp;rsquo;s available for that task. He also gave me some books to read for the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also attended the first #fedora-pune meetup.Following was the agenda for first meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bugyou, filing bugs on broken cloud builds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing new tests for automated atomic/cloud images (Python3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ansible 101 workshop (Please install Anisble on your system before coming down the workshop)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was nice to meet @kushaldas,@siddhesh_p,@yudocca and @kumar_pravin at this meetup.Due to some issues it was held at @ciypro&amp;rsquo;s place very close to our office.In the end of this meetup venue was finalised as the same for future meetups! Fedora meetup mainly focuses on contribution to Fedora and other opensource projects.@kushaldas explained how should we start with opensource contributions and about Fedora Community.@yudocca explained us about his work in Pagure project and also about writing tests for automated atomic/cloud images using Python3.@siddhesh_p started the disscussion with C programming and Bug triaging.Finally @kumar_pravin took a short session on Ansible.He explained us about Ansible,how it works and also explained us how to write the Ansible Playbooks.Playbooks are just the scripts in Ansible in which we mention the tasks that we want to automate.It was very knowledgeble session.Second meetup was fixed in the next week.@kushaldas asked us about the experience in meetup and also asked us how it should be.Most of the attendees were students,so he got awsome inputs.All were curious about this meetup as everyone of us were getting an opportunity learn and discuss on Opensource technologies.I met few new friends in this meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had our annual party this weekend. @shrienk and our team were quite focused on our skit practice.We had a few hours of practice and discussions on the light plans, music, and overall props. Everyone at the office was busy shopping for the party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we had a nice performance at [Jashn] - our annual party. This year we had a new logo that was designed by @shrienk and also the skit was performed with proper music and lights for the first time. It was awesome evening. Red Carpet was the theme for the party.Our Team was rocking the party!! Had a lot of fun! We enjoyed the [Jashn] night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-6&#34;&gt;# Week 6 :&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have started reading the ZeroConf networking book given by @ramkrsna in last week. It is basically similar concept to APIPA in Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s domain of networking that we just had a bit in our networking class at college. The book is written by Stuart Cheshire the one who discovered the Zero Configuration networking and Daniel Steinberg.The book is very nicely written and now I have decided to completely read that book.Reading is really very important which I somehow always skipped in my college days and so I always lacked few basics that I realize now are very important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RDO test day for Mitaka release was scheduled in this week. At RDO&amp;rsquo;s website in the pending list, there were many tasks to start with.I decided to start with the simple one as many people I met, have started with the same. I am working on a definitions list for the components local to RDO. @rbowen have specifically mentioned that it should be strictly local to RDO and duplications should be avoided.Since this was my first time, it was quite confusing for me to start with the contribution. I attended the meeting.Got to know how actually people work in OpenSource projects.I already had my setup of RDO ready on my laptop but was not getting the checkpoint tostart with so after the meeting, I requested @rbowen to explain me how should I start. @rbowen helped me understand the procedure for the same. He was so cool that I wasvery comfortable asking him very basic questions I had in my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#fedora&amp;rsquo;s second Pune meetup was also held at the same venue.Agenda had few topics but as the meetup started with @siddhesh_p &amp;rsquo;s talk on C programming, it was focussed on the same for the entire duration of meetup.@siddhesh_p explained us about C compilers and interpreters, and then topic went on to registers, memory and architectural design of computer processors.We all were really keen to know the things he was discussing, he explained how the C program runs internally that was the shocking part for me.I never heard of those terms in my college and this was the amazing discussion which concluded on the decision of going back to C programming once again for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also started pushing my changes done in shell script on git and also on gerrit for code review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;python3-101&#34;&gt;# Python3 101:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python3 101 meetup was organized by #python-pune group that is hosted by @ciypro, @yudocca, @kushaldas and @kumar_pravin. This meetup was mainly focused for the beginners in Python and for the ones who already know Python2.X but wanted to learn differences between Python2 and Python3.@kushaldas started with absolute basics in Python. He covered variables, lists, dictionaries, file handling, list comprehensions and generators and most of the concepts in python initially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later we discussed few basic differences in Python3 and Python2, for eg. raw_input is now input in Python3.X, in python2 generator has a method next in pyhthon3 generator uses next function call i.e next(x) instead of a method etc. Later on,we did some hands on with Python3, @yudocca gave us some tasks like writing a ls command program in Python using OS modules, fizz buzz program, getting username and password using Python etc. It was an awesome experience for two of my friends who never did anything on Python and also for me to understand basics of it. Next month we will be having Python DevSprint for one day in which we will be discussing on how to contribute in OpenSourcePython projects and do some coding in Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-7&#34;&gt;# Week 7:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started working on some of the live issues,peer-reviewing with the help of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/NeetiDahiya&#34;&gt;@NeetiDahiya&lt;/a&gt;.We had one more intern added to our interns family and yet another box of Doughnuts!. &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; had already asked us to share whatever sessions we had, with the new joinees.@shrienk has asked us to make us new joinees checklist so that it is self-explanatory enough to new joinees to do intial tasks related to our project and avoid confusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are planning to have intern&amp;rsquo;s morning and evening sessions in which everyone of us will take some topics and we will discuss on them as it will help us share our knowledge,help grow our understanding of concepts and learn new things from eachother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Hat - The Journey Begins</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 13:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/blog1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting an internship at Red Hat was like my dream come true! My
parents, at first, thought that I am joking and they never expected that
I would get this internship, but later on when I showed them my
confirmation mail they were happy. Things changed. Mom and Dad, who used
to shout at me every time were now relaxed and then they started
explaining about other responsibilities at my place with a hope that I
would be capable of handling them some day! ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was December 14th, the day when I entered Red Hat, and my journey
with Red Hat begins! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-1-kickstart-of-internship&#34;&gt;# Week 1: Kickstart of Internship !&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first week at Red Hat was very cool! On the very first day,
immediately after our onboarding we started off with setting up our own
machines with Fedora 23. @shrienk, our Team Lead helped us with this
task. Later on, we were introduced to Devang, our Manager and then to
our Mentors. I was very excited to know about my new role and
responsibilities I would have upon me. @NeetiDahiya is my mentor for my
term of internship.She explained us about the workflow of our project
and also took a session on the internal tools we use at Red Hat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile we had some sessions on Email-Etiquette, IRC - ethics and few
others related to our work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https:/twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; sessions - we call them Gyan sessions :D made me realize how
new technologies are emerging and how in the world of open source people
come together to make robust software that help others and the benefits
of sharing knowledge. Part of it I had known by attending one of his
meetups and at Fudcon 2015, that was held in Pune after four years, in
June 2015!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels really awesome to be around with geeks and learn lots of things
that help you in your career. After all, I feel like I am a
geek-under-progress , because I have decided one thing in mind very
clearly i.e no matter whatever happens after my internship program, I
will take away the knowledge that I will gain in this term of 6 months
and continue the legacy of Open Source in my life by contributing to it
and sharing knowledge with others !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was time to get introduced to our entire team. We were introduced and
@shrienk explained us about our team and its workflow. Thanks to
@shrienk, we really liked the way of introduction to our team and
ofcourse, Donuts were nice as well! :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-2-love-the-open-source-way&#34;&gt;# Week 2: Love the Open Source Way !&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, week two started up with new lessons and some work related to our
project. I have heard in few meetups at Red Hat, You get to learn new
things at Red Hat.. every day! and I have already started experiencing
this since my day one at Red Hat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this week,@shrienk asked us to attend the Docathon event organised by
one of our team at Red Hat. It was nice experience, got to know few
people who are responsible for Documentation at Red Hat. I also met some
of my college seniors in this event. Few sessions like Story Telling and
Agile, Email communication, Open Source Culture, Minimalism etc helped
me add new lessons to my knowledge base that would also help me at my
work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also attended a talk on &amp;ldquo;OOO&amp;rdquo; that @NeetiDahiya asked me to attend so
that I can understand how OpenStack is deployed on production
environments. Till now I only knew about DevStack and PackStack.This
talk on OOO, also called as OpenStack on OpenStack or Triple O helped me
know about the actual method of deploying OpenStack. It is OSP Director
that uses some OpenStack environment to deploy on bare metal systems for
production enviornments. This talk covered all the essentials of OOO
that are used to provision and manage resources associated with
OpenStack, and its working, what is under cloud and over cloud etc. Then
later on we started with understanding the Python project structure, Git
Basics followed by some hands on. Hushhh&amp;hellip; there are so many things to
learn and a long way to go&amp;hellip;. I never ever thought of becoming a part
of such an amazing organization and an Open Source community !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am loving the Open Source way !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-3-keep-calm-and-do-your-kaam&#34;&gt;# Week 3: Keep Calm and do your Kaam !!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, by this time in the third week we were slowly getting acquainted
with our work and responsibilities. We had one more member in our
interns family. More two interns were yet to come on board with us. I
hope we all do our best in coming days and make substantial value
addition to our team and our Organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were asked to write the blog during this week and were suggested to
use Pelican. I had never written a single blog before and this was
intended for a reason , so that it would help us track our day to day
activities, and would be helpful in many other ways like, learning
Pelican, designing your own templates, a bit of Python, HTML, CSS,
bootstrap, jinja2, etc. and would also help us improve our written
communication skills. Initially, I started with reading Pelican docs but
later I decided to do a hands on. It&amp;rsquo;s really very awesome. Pelican is
just a static website generator that uses Python and ReStructuredText or
MarkDown to upload your content that is automatically converted to html
in output directory. In one of the session, @rshbhdas explained us about
Jenkins CI/CD workflow related to our project. It was totally new
concept to understand just like we use Jira and Bugzilla as well.Few
tools I had just heard about them but these are the ones with which I
had to get well versed with. @ciypro explained us about Packaging. How
to start with it and how it&amp;rsquo;s actually done in the community-based
projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was last week of the year and we are enjoying our phase of learning.
I did few mistakes, and I keep on doing them but these are the ones who
teach me and help me get better at my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a Team Dinner that week and it was really a very nice experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual on 31st December, right at 12:00 am, me and my friends were at
Bappa&amp;rsquo;s place ( Shrimant Dagdusheth Halwai Temple,Pune ) to get his
blessings for the coming year - 2o16 ! Great start to the New Year !!!
Cheers !! : )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;week-4-tick-tick-tick-time-is-running&#34;&gt;# Week 4 : Tick..tick&amp;hellip;Tick&amp;hellip;.Time is running&amp;hellip;!!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time flies when you are working&amp;hellip;. seems to be true! :D We had
completed our 1st month at Red Hat and there are lots of things we need
to learn. New Year and new resolutions &amp;hellip;. I think it is time to get
serious about career, so I had set my personal Goals and I am trying my
best to achieve them. Sometimes I am finding really very difficult to
work on some tasks but my mentors are really very understanding. They
are helping me at my every blocker I am facing and so it motivates me to
work as well. After all, I am working with all the geeks and I am
willing to be like them some day !! I have started working on RDO:
Deployed it on my Laptop and preparing for Mitaka test day !! :) I will
also start contributing to RDO and then later on start understanding
other upstream projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another round of donuts for our new member in Interns family was ready
!!! @shrienk is his mentor. I have also participated in @shrienk&amp;rsquo;s skit
that we will be performing on our Annual Party this weekend. We will be
attending Fedora meetup happening this week and also Python-Pune meet up
in next week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @NeetiDahiya, my mentor and all other mentors,@shrienk and one
of my college seniors @SuprithG, who is also working in the same team as
I do !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my first blog and I have enjoyed every bit of writing it . Hope
so I would improve on it in my upcoming posts&amp;hellip;. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May the force be with all of us !!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Red Hat Intern | Tech Enthusiast&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>