<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python Pune on Ganesh Kadam&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/tags/python-pune/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python Pune on Ganesh Kadam&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 11:00:12 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://meganeshkadam.github.io/tags/python-pune/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Pune June 2016 meetup</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-june-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 11:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-june-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;python-pune-meetup-june-2016-data-dojo&#34;&gt;Python Pune Meetup June 2016 : Data Dojo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Python Pune Meetup organized the Data Dojo on 25th June 2016 at Red Hat, Pune. This time its was a kind of hackathon for exploring the Python Pandas,NumPy and Matplotlib that we learned in the last seroes of Data Science meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the data sets that were used for Data Dojo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/adult/adult.data&#34;&gt;Adult Data: Male/Female names&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://data.gov.in/resources/indian-railways-time-table-trains-available-reservation-03082015/download&#34;&gt;Train Time Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; explained what are the pre-requisites for Data Dojo, and what actually it means. Later &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; gave us two data sets to explore. Attendees have to create a group of 3 each and choose any one of them or the one of their own choice and upload it to their repo on Git Hub and share it on meetup page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 25 Pythonistas turned up for this hackathon as expected, but the one&amp;rsquo;s who came tried their hands on with Python Pandas. Most of them were intermediates in Python, though every one in this meetup did explored the data sets. Good thing about this meetup was that, most of the attendees knew Pyhton, and just had never heard about Pandas,Numpy and matplotlib. Data Dojo gave them an opportunity to learn these libraries in Python, and take away for them was, Pandas and introductory Data Science skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally asked every one to present their work to all, and the ones who did got some goodies as well!
Here are links to the work done by some attendees :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tanayseven/python_data_dojo&#34;&gt;Tanay Prabhudesai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ketulgupta1995/Python-Data-Dojo&#34;&gt;Ketul Gupta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vksgaikwad3/pypunedojo&#34;&gt;Vikas Gaikwad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chaiku/PyPuneDataDojo2016&#34;&gt;Chaitanya Kukde&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our upcoming Python Pune meetup, we will be learning about the scikit-learn basics.Thanks &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; for giving us this opportunity to volunteer for awesome meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis using Python Pandas</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-may-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 04:30:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-may-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Python Pune meetup was held at Amazatic solutions, on 28th May 2016. This meetup was focused on Data Analysis using Python Pandas for Data Science Series.Below are some of the highlights of this workshop which were covered using Case Study :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Numpy basics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Pandas Data Structures and basics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Loading&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Wrangling (Clean, Transform, Merge)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Data Aggregation and grouping operations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Exploratory Data Analysis and Descriptive Statistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Plotting and Visualization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; was the speaker for this workshop. He is a Data Engineer at NEC Corporation of America and also a regular member of Python Pune Meetup and Data Scientist Meetup of Pune. I missed the first session on Data Science in last month which mainly focused on the basics of Data Science, Machine Learing and Algorithms and related concepts. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; he covered few of the basic concepts in this meetup again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datascience is full framework.Machine learning deals with building models.Two major languages used in Datascience are : # R and Python
Apart from some syntactical differences in R and Python, both the languages offer the datastructure most oftenly used in Datacience i.e
Dataframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a typical Datascience workflow, most of the time of Data Scientists is consumed to get the data,analyze the data,sepeartion of data,and cleaning of data, that means almost 70% of the total work in intial phase. Later comes the actual business logic and model building.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; cleared this understanding about the Data Science.Most of the people wind up enrolling in to some classes and generally don&amp;rsquo;t understand the actual concepts, there is really a need of efforts if you want to be a Data Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We faced few technical issues during the meetup, in the mean time &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan/1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; started with the basics of numpy. The learning curve to be a good Data Scientist, includes the understanding of python libraries:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;python-pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;scikitlearn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following are few comparisions between numpy and python pandas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;numpy&#34;&gt;numpy:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;built for fast array processing, vector operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15 times faster then list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;made for scientific calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eg :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import numpy as np
imprt pandas as pd

ni = np.array(list)
 type (n1) gives o/p :numpy.ndarray

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;numpy function arrange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;7np.arrange(10)  # bydefault int
for float use : np.arrange(10, dtype=np.64)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;python-pandas&#34;&gt;python pandas :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Datastructure series - 1d numpy array stores data. its like column in dataframe context&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;series also has the index and the value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To access values in series :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser1.values

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To acess the value in index :&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser1.index

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can customize the indexes, and can also have duplicates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ser2=[1,211,2,1,2,1,2], index=[a,d,d,s,a,s]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can change the values in series using index&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dataframe is collection of series like excel sheet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More the memory More data can be analysed in python pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about python pandas, here is the beautiful website for beginners which has the cook book by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/b0rk&#34;&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt; and lots of tutorials as well: &lt;a href=&#34;http://pandas.pydata.org/pandas-docs/version/0.15.2/tutorials.html&#34;&gt;Python Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also discussed about the Matplotlib, in one of the case studies.This case study was taken from the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;,a website focused on learning Data Science and also has hackathons for the same.Case Study was about the Titanic-Machine Learning from Disaster.&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; explained python pandas can be used effectively to extract the data from the available resources, and build the usefull models.Matplotlib is the library used to mainly produce the charts related to the data. You can generate plots, histograms, power spectra, bar charts, errorcharts, scatterplots, etc, with just a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we disscusssed about the next meetup in which we will be conducting a Hackathon,in continuation with this meetup and try to do some hands on wiht Python Pandas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ciypro&#34;&gt;@ciypro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; for giving us the opportunity to learn and volunteer for this meetup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are few resources from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/sudarshan1989&#34;&gt;@sudarshan&lt;/a&gt; that we used for this meetup:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sudarshan1413/python_pandas_meetup_2016&#34;&gt;Python Pune Data Analysis with Pandas&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cin.ufpe.br/~embat/Python%20for%20Data%20Analysis.pdf&#34;&gt;Python for Data Analysis Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Pune March 2016 meetup</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-march-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 12:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/python-march-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Python Pune Meetup March 2016 was organized at Amazatic Solutions on 26th March 2016. Following was the agenda for this meetup :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshop : Vim &amp;amp; frameworks by Devchandra L&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk1 : Libvert Programming API by Amol Kahat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Talk2 : Fedora Hubs by Dhriti Shikhar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@cyipro started the meetup initially with an introduction to Python and OpenSource. The majority of attendees were students so it was very helpful for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amol Kahat started with the first talk of this meet up on libvirt-api he is a Red Hat intern. libvert is a toolkit to interact with the virtualization capabilities of recent versions of Linux. It is a free and opensource software available under GPL license. Amol explained about the virtualization technology, hypervisors and how the libvert-api is different from the other available options. To know more information on libvirt-apis, here is the link :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://libvirt.org/&#34;&gt;Libvert&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@vega_yaa is the organizer of Pune Vim Users Group. The main motto of this group is to help people start using vim and to share knowledge about the same. @vega_yaa started with vim workshop after Amol&amp;rsquo;s talk by explaining a little history of vi and vim, later on also explained few differences in bertween them.It was for all the novices as well as for the people who already use vim for their daily use but are unaware of the vim&amp;rsquo;s power. Starting with very basics, he explained why we should use vim, and its magic once you get used to it. Attendees got a hands-on session on vim, for example starting with how you should open multiple files using vim, how to use alias, Buffermode in vim, various options like split, vsplit, tabnewfile, code folding in vim etc.Though it sounds very simple, knowing essentials of vim will definitely boost the productivity. Here are the slides for this workshop :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PuneVimUser/magical-vim&#34;&gt;Vim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@DhritiShikhar gave a talk on Fedora Hubs post vim workshop. She is a final year Engineering student from a Sinhagad college of Engineering, Pune and very active in OpenSource contributions. She is one of the owners of Fedora Hubs project as well. She explained why this project was started and also showed how one should start with the contribution to any open source project. Fedora Hubs is still in active development stage and due for release in next 3 months. Here is the link for the Fedora Hubs project on Pagure :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pagure.io/fedora-hubs&#34;&gt;Fedora Hubs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally the meetup ended with a good response and feedbacks from attendees. We had some discussion for next meetup. It was as a good learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python3 devsprint2016#1</title>
      <link>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/devsprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 01:00:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://meganeshkadam.github.io/post/devsprint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Knowledge is Power.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;#python-pune&lt;/strong&gt; meetup organized &lt;em&gt;devsprint#1&lt;/em&gt; this Saturday i.e on 20-02-2016. It was the first dev sprint for me as well and my first meet up as a host for the day, thanks to @cyipro and @yudocca for giving me this opportunity. This dev sprint was quite different than the previous ones. We have asked attendees to select the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; projects of their own choice to work on during the dev sprint. There were many of them who could find themselves suitable projects and started working on, but few were completely new to &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contribution and so it took some time for them to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very beginning of this dev sprint, @ciypro explained about getting started with the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contributions and how one should find the projects of his/her own choice. We found most of them had the same problem in getting the projects of their interests as there are a number of projects available and for newbies, it is really very difficult to get the starting point for the &lt;strong&gt;#OpenSource&lt;/strong&gt; contribution. Here are few links where I searched for the projects and helped few attendees to start with: - &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatcanidoforfedora.org/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/openstack/+bugs&#34;&gt;OpenStack&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatcanidoformozilla.org/&#34;&gt;Mozilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have selected the bug from link &lt;a href=&#34;https://bugs.launchpad.net/congress/+bug/1415199&#34;&gt;Congress&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;OpenStack low hanging fruits&lt;/em&gt; . Here is the link for the link &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/openstack/congress&#34;&gt;Congress&lt;/a&gt; on git. Currently, the installation is available only for Debian. @cyipro have suggested me to update the process for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CentOS&lt;/em&gt; and send a patch for the same. Quite easier for me to get started! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this dev sprint, I got to know how you should get help for the projects you are working on and also the end result of working collaboratively on a single project. One of the attendees was not able to find the project, but he started working on one of the projects with few others at dev sprint and at the end of the dev sprint this group was actually able to send a small patch for that project. They all were first timers and were happy to work collaboratively for that bug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this was experimental dev sprint, not all of the attendees could find the projects and send the patches, but everyone was satisfied at the end of the day, because for many this meet up formed as a platform to learn and start with #OpenSource contributions. We had a feedback session at the end from each of the attendees and we got many positive feedbacks for this dev sprint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a nice experience for me and got many new things added to my knowledge base. I have started preparing for more such dev sprints to happen in coming days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learning is the eye of the mind. Keep Learning&lt;/em&gt; -French Proverb&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>